Artem Roma

Software Engineer

Lviv

Ukraine

1 +38 (050) 047 0891

✓ fuzzy.finder@gmail.com

in artem-roma

Profile

I am a skilled software engineer with 10 years of experience in building product platforms and web applications. Throughout my career, I have successfully delivered products in diverse and multicultural teams.

I have a goal-oriented mindset and value the same in my colleagues. I enjoy deeply engaging with the product, understanding customer needs, and ensuring high-quality support after release.

I am drawn to organizations that prioritize trust and transparency, as I believe they create a positive and collaborative work environment.

Technical Skills

- O Python, Go
- O FastAPI, Flask, SQLAlchemy, AsyncIO
- REST, GraphQL
- O Docker, Kubernetes, Flux CD
- CircleCI, Jenkins
- PostgreSQL, Redis
- AWS Lambda, Athena, S3, Glue, Redshift, Aurora, Kinesis, CloudWatch, Route53 etc.
- Terraform
- Graphana

Experience

2020–2023 Sr. Software Engineer, VGS

- O Build a billing system for the product
 - billing models definition
 - data platfrom architecture and implementation
 - integration with the payment services providers
 - build web control portal for customers
 - build analytical dashboard service for customers
- Develop product observability services
- O Develop a cloud (AWS) data warehouse solution

2017–2019 **Software Engineer**, *DataRobot*

Build a platform for the prediction model automation product

2017 **Software Engineer**, SoftServe Inc.

Build e-commerce platform for one of the company customers

2013–2017 **Software Engineer**, *Mirantis*

Build a platfrom for OpenStack cluster management on customer infrastructure

2013 Software Engineer, Speedflow

Build platform for VoIP class 4 softswitch product

Education

2012–2013 **Specialist degree in Computer Engineering**, Kharkiv National University of Radio

and Electronics

2008–2012 BSc in Computer Engineering, Kharkiv National University of Radio and

Electronics

Languages

English Upper-intermediate

Ukrainian Native

Interests

Product delivery

Distributed systems

O Data intensive systems and data platforms

Observability

Developer tooling

Product management